Contact

danishhussain47@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/danish-hussain-78491a52 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Agile Methodologies Leadership Management

Languages

Urdu (Native or Bilingual) English

Danish Hussain

Software Consultant || Core Banking Applications || Alternate Delivery Channel || Surround Systems || Implementations and Integrations

Pakistan

Summary

A Software and Business Consultant with experience in delivering projects to a consistently high standard in a leading commercial bank with a commitment to improve the implementation of controls and business processes of software applications.

I have exposure of IT related banking and managerial issues of a leading commercial organization, while maintaining the relevant combination of academics. I am able to assist and advise all level of managements, enquiries, new product launches and in day to day strategic modifications and decisions.

Experience

Bank Al Habib Limited Senior Business Analyst April 2013 - Present (9 years)

Center Point Tower

Business Model Reengineering with IT Solution

- Manage Idea to shelf execution of all IT solution, applications, and software, maintain centralized data integration, team leader that creates active liaison with stake holders to achieve company goals.
- Designed Inter Branch Pay Cash, Receive Deposits and Fund Transfer System for swift transactions across branches with on-time alerts.
- Idea to shelf execution and launch of DIRECT DEBIT FACILITY for scheduled transactions and utility bill payments.
- Level-up the Utility bill Payment system by providing one window IT solution for multiple deposits at a time using barcode devices.
- Digitalize conventional Payment Orders to Banker's Cheque Application that facilitates business sector and vendors for direct deposits to customers and payable anywhere.

- Proactively manages perform regular analysis of each banking application in liaison with IBM and IBM Software Performance to identify bottle neck areas that may create issue in future.
- Manage Oracle Fluxcube to enhance production and data integration.
- Complete handling of Cash Over Counter and Integration of RIA, IME, TRANSFAST, WORLREMMIT and INSTANT CASH on COC Portal.

IT Solution for Regulatory and Business Markets

- Introduced Gateway to Equity Market Application integrated with stock market to buy and sell shares through direct transitions.
- Moderated Biometric Verification Project to comply with Regulatory Authorities, maintain internal data similar to NADRA protocols.
- Introduced Biometric ATM system to facilitate card-less transactions.
- Moderated ASAAN Account projects for clients that want to remain under caps of amounts set by Govt. of Pakistan.

Operational Management

- Responsible for Data Integration of Sub-branches when transformed to Controlling branches.
- Introduced Centralized data base via clubbing segregated data of all branches, also maintain back-up of branch wise segregated data.

EmbTrans

Software Engineer

February 2013 - October 2013 (9 months)

Karachi

- Managed testing for Web Applications, Facebook applications for any performance issue, ensure on-time facilitation to clients.
- Designed and implemented automated test scripts.

Emirates Islamic

Intern

June 2008 - August 2008 (3 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

• Established and communicated strategic materials management policies for ENI Field Operations, works closely with the HOD's Drilling, Engineering, Production, Finance, and Procurement to ensure the most effective supply chain operations.

Education

Muhammad Ali Jinnah University

Masters in Computer Science, Software Project Management · (2013)

Hamdard University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.)in Computer Science, Computer Science